<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forecast on Boris Blagov</title>
    <link>/tags/forecast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forecast on Boris Blagov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/forecast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Economic Forecast </title>
      <link>/project/gd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/gd/</guid>
      <description>The Joint Economic Forecast is prepared bi-annually in spring and in autumn on behalf of the Federal Ministry for Economic Affairs and Energy. The forecast is prepared by:
 German Institute for Economic Research (DIW Berlin) ifo Institute - Leibniz Institute for Economic Research at the University of Munich in cooperation with the KOF Swiss Economic Institute – ETH Zurich Kiel Institute for the World Economy (IfW) Halle Institute for Economic Research (IWH) – Member of the Leibniz Association RWI – Leibniz Institute for Economic Research in cooperation with the Institute for Advanced Studies in Vienna  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RWI Business Cycle Forecasts</title>
      <link>/project/bcf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/bcf/</guid>
      <description>The RWI &amp;ndash; Leibniz Institute for Economic Research conducts a quarterly analysis of the business cycle developments in Germany and provides a short term forecast (up to 2 years). This analysis includes a detailed forecast for the internatinoal economy bi-annualy (March and September). Below you will find a collection of the forecasts that I have taken part of.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>